#### **OLGA BOLSHCHIKOVA**

Portfolio website: <a href="http://bolshchikova.com">http://bolshchikova.com</a>
760 North 7th St., San Jose, CA 95112
(347) 873-7216 • <a href="mailto:olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com">olga.bolshchikova@gmail.com</a>
Fully Work Authorized • No Visa Sponsorship Required

## **SUMMARY:**

Analytical, driven, and creative visual designer with 10+ years of experience enhancing brands through print and web design and production roles. Able to lead design projects and service business needs through production, design, and formatting of creative materials.

#### **KEY SKILLS:**

- Experience in design and layout of variety of print and web assets, preparing files for print, responsive design
- Expertise in composition, typography, image manipulation, masking, color correction, digital photo retouching using Photoshop
- Skilled at UX/UI design for websites, landing pages, e-commerce, mobile apps for iOS
- Proficient at Adobe Creative Suite (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat Pro, Illustrator), Adobe Muse, Sketch3, MS (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Keynote on both MAC and Windows
- Knowledge of HTML5, CSS3 (hand-on coding). Familiar with WordPress, Dreamweaver
- Prototyping with Balsamig, Draw.io, InVision
- Ability to complete a high volume of projects on time and on budget, work well in a deadline-driven environment with a keen eye for detail
- Capacity to perform well in a team environment as well as individually, with minor supervision
- Ability to learn and use new technologies and challenging concepts quickly
- Fluent in English and Russian

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

**Graphic Designer / Production Artist BlueApple Design, Menlo Park, CA** 

Full service design studio

Created 10+ e-books, whitepapers by following corporate brand, identity, and guidelines (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator)
under tight deadline

**Graphic Designer** 

3/2015 - 3/2016

3/2016 - Present

Safe Drive Systems, New York, NY

Developer and distributor of advanced, active auto safety technologies

- Designed user-centered banner ads, landing pages, e-brochures, and flyers from a design concept to completion (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator), that increased product sales by 18%
- Created animated presentations (Keynote, PowerPoint) for potential car buyers in dealerships and for the product promotion on the company website
- Redesigned the website blog section for better user interaction and SEO optimization. The traffic to the blog was increased by over 50%
- Worked closely with the marketing team to design and present several versions of advertising mockups for discussion at stakeholder briefings. It helped the company develop the right brand strategy of the product

### **Graphic Designer / Production Artist**

9/2014 - 8/2015

IMR, New York, NY

Nonprofit, nonpartisan public policy organization—a think tank—with offices in New York and Washington DC

- Supervised the redesign, layout, and preparing for printing the "IMR Review" quarterly corporate magazine. Implemented image
  manipulations, color correction, photo retouching, vector graphics (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat, Illustrator) to get better visual
  perception of the magazine and thereby improve its quality
- Designed, laid out, and produced multipage journalistic reports (Adobe Creative Suite) from the initial concept through prepress
  under tight deadlines with no errors, which were successfully presented at a conference in Washington, D.C., and at a political
  discussion forum in NYC

#### Sr. Graphic Designer / Technical Editor

12/2000 - 5/2014

Integral LLC, Yekaterinburg, Russia

Publishing House / Advertising Agency and partner of Pfizer, Nestle, Royal Canin, Merial

- Supervised the design, layout and production of 5 monthly scientific-practical magazines and 3 monthly newspapers with a circulation of over 15000 copies each edition, which were developed from scratch and successfully distributed in 46 regions of Russia
- Designed, laid out, and produced creative materials including ads, posters, newsletters, printed brochures, booklets (InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat) with vector diagrams and infographics (Illustrator), brand identity, stationery, digital banners, and presentations (PowerPoint) to meet the requirements of local and national companies
- Worked closely with manufacturing and scientific companies to implement their idea and solve their design problems
- Working directly with the marketing team and software engineers to create, design and update content of website pages (WordPress), online media, and hands-on coding experience with HTML/CSS, that improved client transactions by 15-20%
- Reduced about 30% client printing costs by interviewing and selecting the best offset/digital print vendor

### **EDUCATION:**

# Bachelor of Science (BS), Engineering Physics

Ural Polytechnic Institute (Ural Federal University), Yekaterinburg, Russia Ranked 7<sup>th</sup> best Russian universities (Web ometrics Ranking of World Universities)

### PRPOFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT:

- Design and Make Infographics (Project-Centered online course), Coursera, 7–8/2016
- **UX/UI Design Course**, Bloc Inc. online education company with intensive mentor-led programs for aspiring developers and designers (<a href="https://www.bloc.io/ux-design-bootcamp">https://www.bloc.io/ux-design-bootcamp</a>), 8–12/2015
- Human-Computer Interaction online course, Coursera, 7-8/2014
- HTML & CSS online course, Codecademy, 4-5/2013